This is the story of how I died.
这个故事里我会契办子
But don't worry, this is a fun story, and the truth is, it isn't even mine.
不过安啦，这葛是喜剧 事实上，我也不算主角
This is the story of a girl named Rapunzel.
故事的主角是一位叫乐仇的女孩
And it starts with the sun.
一切得从太阳说起
Once upon a time, a single drop of sunlight fell from the heavens.
很久很久以前 有一滴阳光和从天堂掉落几则
And from this small drop of sun grew a magic golden flower.
这一小滴阳光泣落处 长出一双神奇的金花
It had the ability to heal the sick and injured.
它具有疗伤治病的能力
You see that old woman over there? You might want to remember her.
看见那个欧巴又没? 你们最好记住她
She's kind of important.
她有点重要
Centuries passed
遇了好玫世纪
and a hop, skip and a boat ride away there grew a kingdom.
附近不速的地方有了一个王国
The kingdom was ruled by a beloved king and queen.
那里的国王和王后很受人民爱戴
And the queen was about to have a baby.
王后就快要生了
But she got sick.
可是她病了
Really sick.
病的很重
She was running out of time,
她来日不多了
and that's when people Start to look for a miracle.
这时人们便祈盼出现奇中
Or in this case, a magic golden flower.
而那就是，和神奇的金花
! told you she'd be important.
我就说遇她有点重要吧
Instead of sharing the sun's gift,
她音当於分享太阳的礼物
this woman, Mother Gothel, hoarded its healing power
这女人，蓝索妈妈，霸估疗疯神花
and used it to keep herself young for hundreds of years.
用来保持自己的青春永台
And all she had to do was sing a special song.
而她只需唱一首特别的歌就行
Flower, gleam and glow
神被黄金花
Let your power shine
闪耀像太阳
Make the clock reverse
让时间倒转
Bring back what once was mine
带我回到遇往
What once was mine
回到通往
You get the gist. She sings to it, she turns young. Creepy, right?
对啦，她对它唱歌就爸年翅 拉吧 ?
We found it!
找到了 !
The magic of the golden flower healed the queen.
金花的神力治净了王后
A healthy baby girl, a princess was born, with beautiful golden hair.
一个健康的宰裤，公主诞生了 她有一头美畦的金要
I'll give you a hint, that's Rapunzel.
提示你们一下吧，那就是乐佩
To celebrate her birth,
为了庆祝她出生
the king and queen launched a flying lantern into the sky.
国王和王后一起施放天灯
And for that one moment, everything was perfect.
当下，一切都很完美
And then that moment ended.
但好景不常
Flower, gleam and glow
神被黄金花
Let your power shine
闪耀像太阳
Make the clock...
让时间倒…
Gothel broke into the castle, stole the child,
葛索溜进城堡，抱走孩子
and just like that, gone!
就这样，内人 !
The kingdom searched and searched, but they could not find the princess.
全国上下到处寻找 但是印找不到公主
For deep within the forest, in a hidden tower,
在森林深处，一座隐密的高塔上
Gothel raised the child as her own.
葛索把孩子当成自己的义大
Save what has been lost
重拾起失落
Bring back what once was mine
带我回到遇往
What once was mine
回到通往
Gothel had found her new magic flower,
葛索找到她新的神奇金花
but this time, she was determined to keep it hidden.
不遇这灾，她决心把它藏起来
Why can't I go outside?
为什么我不能出去?
The outside world is a dangerous place,
外面的世界很危险
filled with horrible, selfish people.
充满了可怕、自私的人
You must stay here, where you're safe.
称要待在这壬，这和里才安全
Do you understand, flower?
娩明和白吗，小花?
Yes, Mommy.
是的，妈味
But the walls of that tower could not hide everything.
不遇那高塔之芷扰法遮掩一切
Each year, on her birthday,
每年，在她生日那天
the king and queen released thousands of lanterns into the sky
国王和王后施放数以千计的天煤
in hope that one day their lost princess would return.
祈难有一天 失踪的公主会回来
Well, l guess Pascal's not hiding out here.
我想帕斯卡没有躲在这壬
Gotcha!
抓到了 !
That's 22 for me. How about 23 out of 45?
我赢22次了 改成45战23腾好不好 ?
Okay. Well, what do you want to do?
好吧，那你想做什么 ?
Yeah. I don't think so. l like it in here, and so do you.
是啊，我可不这广想 我喜欢待在里面，你也一样
Come on, Pascal. It's not so bad in there.
拜旗，帕斯卡 竺在里面也还好吧
Seven a.m., the usual morning lineup
新的一天就在早上七点展开
Start on the chores And sweep till the floor's all clean
整理家务，先把地板探乾泽
Polish and wax, do laundry and mop and shine up
然后打腊，洗衣再把地板探亮
Sweep again and by then it's, like, 7:15
再护一灵，但时间只遇十五分
And so I'll read a book Or maybe two or three
於是我读一本或雨三本的书
lll add a few new paintings to my gallery
在我的书室里增添更多作品
ll play guitar and knit and cook and basically
弹吉他，织毛衣，最和后再来做癸
Just wonder when will my life begin?
不知道人生何时改释
Then after lunch it's puzzles and darts and baking
午餐遇和后拼图射屎针和烘焙
Papier-maché, a bit of ballet and chess
人向个面具，然后芭蔓西洋棋
Pottery and ventriloquy, candle-making
隐世还有腹语，做点手工星烛
Then I'll stretch, maybe sketch Take a climb, sew a dress
伸巾腰，画些首 再攀岩，缝让服
And I'll reread the books If l have time to spare
我又再读一回 已经读遇的韦
lll paint the walls some more I'm sure there's room somewhere
想找点空白处增加更多色彩
And then I'll brush and brush and brush and brush my hair
我一坎又一灵整理我的头聂
Stuck in the same place I've always been
困在一成不变的塔里
And I'll keep wondering and wondering and wondering and wondering
我不停在想 整个人都陷在思绪和里
When will my life begin?
人生何了时并始
Tomorrow night
条静夜空
the lights will appear
愿望将会实现
on my birthday each year
将会再赤出现
What is it like
在发光上处
out there where they glow
是什么模样
Now that I'm older
长大了的我
Mother might just let me go
不知何时会自由
Wow! I could get used to a view like this.
这美景真是百看不原
Rider, come on!
雪德，快点 !
Hold on. Yep. I'm used to it. Guys, I want a castle.
等等鸣，对，我喜霓 十位，我要一座城堡
We do this job, you can buy your own castle.
干了这一票，你可以自己买城堡
-Hay fever? -Yeah.
-鼻子通敏 ? -对
Wait! Hey, wait!
等等1!等一等 !
Can't you picture me in a castle of my own? Because I certainly can.
我自己的城堡耶，我想到都会笑
All the things we've seen, and it's only 8:00 in the morning!
经历了这一切 也才早上八点而已 !
Gentlemen, this is a very big day!
各位，今天是很重要的一天 !
This is it! This is a very big day, Pascal.
就是今天 ! 今天是很重要的一天，帕斯卡
I'm finally going to do it. I'm going to ask her.
我下定决心，一定要间她
Rapunzel!
乐休 !
Let down your hair!
放下人的头聂 !
It's time!
时候到了 !
I know, I know. Come on. Don't let her see you.
我知道、我知道 来，别让她看到你了
Rapunzel! I'm not getting any younger down here!
乐佩 ! 我等你等的都老了 !
Coming, Mother!
来了，杂 !
Hi. Welcome home, Mother.
束迎回家，杂
Rapunzel, how you manage to do that
乐侣，人是怎广做到的
every single day without fail.
每天都这广顺手
It looks absolutely exhausting, darling.
看起来很累人的，乖女儿
Oh, it's nothing.
这没什么啦
Then I don't know why it takes so long.
那我就不明白你干交拖这广久
Oh, darling, I'm just teasing.
厅爱的，我要你的啦
All right.
好吧
So, Mother, as you know tomorrow is a very big day...
那个，妈 称知道明天是个大日子…
Rapunzel, look in that mirror.
乐修，看著那面镜子
You know what I see?
人知道我看到什么吐 ?
l see a strong, confident, beautiful young lady.
我看到一位坚强、有自信的美女
Oh, look, you're here, too.
人看，也在里面呢
I'm just teasing. Stop taking everything so seriously.
我并玩笑的啦，别老是这广顾元嘛
Okay. So, Mother, as I was saying, tomorrow is...
好吧，妈，我刚刚说明天…
Rapunzel, Mother's feeling a little run-down.
乐修，妈妈有点累了
Would you sing for me, dear? Then we'll talk.
唱歌给我孤好吗 ? 我们之和后再谈
Of course, Mother.
当然好，杂杂
Flower, gleam and glow Let your power shine
神被黄金花 闪耀像太阳
Make the clock reverse Bring back what once was mine
让时间倒转 带我回到遇往
Heal what has been hurt Change the Fates' design
疗疯蓝伤痛 请赐我力量
Save what has been lost Bring back what once was mine
重拾起失落 带我回到遇往
-Rapunzel! -So, Mother,
-乐佩 ! -妈妈
earlier l was saying tomorrow is a big day, and you didn't respond.
我刚说明天是个大日子 人没反应
So, I'm just going to tell you, it's my birthday!
我只是要告诉你 明天是我生日 !
-Ta-da! -No, no, no. Can't be.
-好棒 ! -不，不可能的
I distinctly remember. Your birthday was last year.
我很清楚记得 人生日去年过明了
That's the funny thing about birthdays. They're kind of an annual thing.
这就是生日最好玩的地方 生日年年有
Mother, I'm turning 18, and I wanted to ask...
始，我要满18茂了
What I really want for this birthday...
我今年生日真正想要的…
Actually what I wanted for quite a few birthdays now...
其实是我这北年生日 一直想要的…
Rapunzel, please, stop with the mumbling.
乐仇，不要碎碎哈
You know how I feel about the mumbling. Blah-blah-blah-blah.
你知道我对碎碎哈的感觉
It's very annoying! I'm just teasing. You're adorable.
吵死人了 ! 开玩笑的啦，很可爱
l love you so much, darling.
我很爱你，亲爱的
I want to see the floating lights.
我想去看天上的光点
What?
什么 ?
I was hoping you would take me to see the floating lights.
我希望你能带我去看天上的光点
You mean the stars.
炼是说星星
That's the thing.
我就是想说这个
I've charted stars, and they're always constant.
我研究遇星座图 它们位置狗是不变
But these, they appear every year on my birthday, Mother.
可是这些 都是每年我生日才出现
Only on my birthday.
只有在我生日这天
And I can't help but feel like they're meant for me.
我觉得它们是为了我而出现的
I need to see them, Mother.
我要去看它们，妈
And not just from my window, in person.
不是从窗户看，而是现场亲眼看
I have to know what they are.
我要知道那些是什么
You want to go outside? Why, Rapunzel...
人想出去外面 ? 真是的，乐个…
Look at you, as fragile as a flower
你就像是脆弱的花采
Still a little sapling, just a sprout
你膛是棵小机，刚发菠
You know why we stay up in this tower
人知道贺何在塔里窗
-l know, but... -That's right.
-我知道，可是… -那是
To keep you safe and sound, dear
要保护你的安全
Guess I always knew this day was coming
早芒预料这天将会来临
Soon but not yet
有些事
Shh! Trust me, pet
我要你学会
Mother knows best
我最了解
Listen to your mother
再背定也不过
It's a scary world out there
多六险恶的世界
Mother knows best
我最了解
One way or another Something will go wrong
名有一天 人会知道我说的
! swear
都对
Ruffians, thugs, poison ivy, quicksand
土匪、流谍、有毒藤蔓、流沙
Cannibals and snakes, the plague
食人族和蛇、瘟疫
-No! -Yes.
-不，可是… -对
Also large bugs Men with pointy teeth
大焦昆总、暴牙男人
And stop! No more, you'll just upset me
还有更多让我乱法形容
Mother's right here Mother will protect you
我在这壬，妈杂会保护你
Darling, here's what I suggest
给你所有的一切
Skip the drama Stay with Mama
职我的益，现在做因
Mother knows best
我最了解
Take it from your mumsy
我最了解，若只有你自己
On your own, you won't survive
不可能会遇的好
Sloppy, underdressed Immature, clumsy
服装不得体，这广孩子气
Please, they'll eat you up alive
人会遭受到伤害
Gullible, naive Positively grubby
好吃又好奇，生活豚吕扼比
Plus, ! believe, getting kind of chubby
称的下巴，看来有点油腊
I'm just saying ‘cause I wuv you
因为爱你才提醒隶
Mother understands Mother's here to help you
妈妈最可贵，妈妈会帮助人
All l have is one request
只希望你了解
-Rapunzel? -Yes?
-乐佩? -是的
Don't ever ask to leave this tower again.
不准再提要鸠并这座高塔
Yes, Mother.
是的，妈妈
l love you very much, dear.
我很爱你，裤中
Don't forget it
不要忘记
You'll regret it
永速爱你
Mother knows best
我最了解
Ta-ta! I'll see you in a bit, my flower!
拜拜 ! 待会见，我的小花采 !
I'll be here.
我会守在这壬
Oh, no.
不、不
This is bad. This is very, very bad.
这真错糙，太糟糙了
This is really bad.
这真的太错长了
They just can't get my nose right.
老是把我的眉子书这广梗
Who cares?
谁在手啊?
It's easy for you to say. You guys look amazing.
你们当然乱所谓 你们看起来印呆了
All right. Okay. Give me a boost and I'll pull you up.
先推我上去，我再拉你们上来
Give us the satchel first.
先把包包给我们
I can't believe that after all we've been through together, you don't trust me?
我们一起经历了这广多事 你们竟然不相信我?
Now help us up, pretty boy!
输你帮我们了，小和白脸 !
Sorry, my hands are full.
抱娄，我的手没空
What?
什么 ?
Rider!
雪德 !
Retrieve that satchel at any cost!
一定要追回那个包包 !
Yes, sir!
是，长官!
We got him now, Maximus.
我们还到他了，券西玛斯
Come on, fleabag! Forward!
快点，自马儿 ! 前进啊 !
No.
不行
Stop it! Stop it! Give it to me! Give me that!
停!停!给我! 把包包给我 !
Alone at last.
终从只有我们了
Okay. I've got a person in my closet.
好，我的衣杠里有一个人
I've got a person in my closet.
我的衣权里有一个人
I've got a person in my closet!
我的衣权里有一个人 !
Too weak to handle myself out there, huh, Mother?
我太邓能，没法保护自己?
Well, tell that to my frying pan.
去跟我的锅子讲吧
Rapunzel!
乐休 !
Let down your hair!
放下人的头聂 !
One moment, Mother!
马上来，嫣杂 !
I have a big surprise!
我有一个大车喜 !
I do, too!
我也有 !
I bet my surprise is bigger!
我敢说我的车喜比较大 !
l seriously doubt it.
这我可不敢确定哦
I brought back parsnips. I'm going to make hazelnut soup for dinner.
我带了防风草回来 我要者标子省汤给你喝
Your favorite. Surprise!
你最爱喝的，募喜 !
Well, Mother, there's something I want to tell you.
妈妈 ，我有话要跟你训
Oh, Rapunzel, you know I hate leaving you after a fight.
乐休，我不喜数吵架之后扔下你
Especially when I've done absolutely nothing wrong.
可是我也没做错什么事情
I've been thinking a lot about what you said earlier.
我想过你之前跟我说遇的证
I hope you're not still talking about the stars.
我希望你不要再提星星的事了
"Floating lights," and, yes, I'm leading up to that.
“是天上的光是” 对，我正要提哆
Because I really thought we dropped the issue, sweetheart.
我想我们已经谈遇这件事了
No, Mother, I'm just saying,
不是的，妈妈，我只是想说
you think I'm not strong enough to handle myself out there.
人认鸭我不金强壮 不能保访自己
I know you're not strong enough to handle yourself out there.
我知道你不锡强于
-But if you just... -We're done talking about this.
-可是你… -这个我们已经谈遇了
-Trust me! I know what I'm... -Rapunzel.
-相信我 ! 我知道我… -乐保
-Oh, come on! -Enough with the lights!
-和拜旗 ! -说钓了没 !
You are not leaving this tower! Ever!
人不准认并这座塔 ! 永记不准 !
Great. Now I'm the bad guy.
好了，这下我成了款人了
All l was going to say, Mother, is that...
我想说的只是…
I know what I want for my birthday now.
我知道我生日想要什么了
And what is that?
是什么呢?
New paint.
新的颜料
The paint made from the white shells you once brought me.
那种用和白忠规做的顿料 称以前买通的
That is a very long trip, Rapunzel. Almost three days’ time.
那要跑好下才买得到 要将近三天的时间
I just thought it was a better idea than the stars.
我只是想，那名比星星好吧
You'll be all right on your own?
人确定自己一个人没关像?
I know I'm safe as long as I'm here.
只要我在塔祷，我知道我很安全
I'll be back in three days' time.
我遇三天就回来
l love you very much, dear.
我很爱你，裤中
Is this hair?
这是头肥 ?
Struggling... Struggling is pointless.
择扎…择扎是没有用的
I know why you're here, and I'm not afraid of you.
我知道你贺什么会求 我一点也不怕你
What?
什么 ?
Who are you? And how did you find me?
你是谁? 你又是怎广找到我的?
I know not who you are, nor how I came to find you.
我不知道你是谁 我也不是来找的
But may I just say...
不明我只想说…
Hi.
娩好
How you doing? The name's Flynn Rider.
人好吗 ?我叫费林雷德
How's your day going?
称日子通的好吗?
Who else knows my location, Flynn Rider?
还有谁知道我在这，费林雷德 ?
-All right, blondie. -Rapunzel.
-好吧，金权妹 -我叫乐傈
Gesundheit. Here's the deal.
人好，事情是这样的
l was in a situation, gallivanting through the forest.
我遇上事情，晃过了森林
Il came across your tower and...
我发现你的塔，然后…
Where is my satchel?
我的包包啊 ?
I've hidden it. Somewhere you'll never find it.
我藏起来了，你永下找不到的
It's in that pot, isn't it?
在那个鲸里，对吧 ?
Would you stop that?
列关了，好吗?
Now it's hidden where you'll never find it.
现在我藏在你找不到的地方了
So, what do you want with my hair? To cut it?
你想对我的头权怎样 ? 疯看它?
-What? -Sell it?
-什么 ? -拿去喜 ?
No! Listen, the only thing l want to do with your hair
不 ! 贩著 我对你的头紧只有一个想法
is to get out of it, literally.
就是甩掉它，就这样
Wait. You don't want my hair?
等等，你不要我的头权 ?
Why on earth would I want your hair?
我干骂想要你的头权 ?
Look, I was being chased, l saw a tower, I climbed it.
我被人追，我看到塔，我朴上它
-End of story. -You're telling the truth?
-故事结束 -你说的是实话 ?
Yes.
对
I know. l need someone to take me.
我知道，我需要有人人带我去
I think he's telling the truth, too.
我想他说的也是实话
He doesn't have fangs. But what choice do I have?
他没尖牙，不遇我有什么玩择 ?
Okay, Flynn Rider, I'm prepared to offer you a deal.
好吧，费林雷德 我准备跟你提一个交易
-Deal? -Look this way.
-交易 ? -看这站
Do you know what these are?
你知道这些是什么吐?
You mean the lantern thing they do for the princess?
是说他们为公主放的天煤 ?
Lanterns? I knew they weren't stars.
天炬 ? 我就知道不是星星
Well, tomorrow evening,
明天晚上
they will light the night sky with these lanterns.
他们会用这些天灯点亮夜空
You will act as my guide, take me to these lanterns,
你要当我的窗壮 带我去看这些天煤
and return me home safely.
然后再安全回家
Then, and only then, will l return your satchel to you.
到那时，也只有到那时 我才会把你的包包还给你
Yeah.
是哦
No can do.
办不到
Unfortunately the kingdom and I aren't exactly simpatico at the moment,
很不幸目前我和整个王国不对盘
so won't be taking you anywhere.
所以我不能带你去任何地方
Something brought you here, Flynn Rider.
有某个力量带你来此，费林雷德
Call it what you will,
随你怎广称呼它
-fate, destiny... -A horse.
-人命运、天意… -是一匹马
So I have made the decision to trust you.
所以我决定要相信你
A horrible decision, really.
真是个糟莓的决定
But trust me when I tell you this.
不遇请相信我
You can tear this tower apart brick by brick,
你可以把这个塔拆个钴光
but without my help, you will never find your precious satchel.
可是没有我的帮助 你将永速找不到你的实贝包包
Let me get this straight.
让我弄清楚
l take you to see the lanterns, bring you back home,
我带你去看天烃，带回家
and you'll give me back my satchel?
你就把包包膛给我?
And when I promise something, I never, ever break that promise.
当我说我保证的时候 我绝对不会过反诺言
Ever.
永速不会
All right, listen. I didn't want to have to do this,
好吧，匠著，我闪不想这广做
but you leave me no choice.
不遇娩我别扰选择
Here comes the smolder.
看我的爱欧眼神大绝招了
This is kind of an off day for me. This doesn't normally happen.
今天我状况不好，通常很有用的
Fine! I'll take you to see the lanterns.
好啦 ! 我带你去看天煤
Really?
真的?
You broke my smolder.
毁了我的大绝招
Are you coming, blondie?
你来不来啊，金要妹 ?
Look at the world so close And I'm halfway to it
看这世界万物台在我的脚底
Look at it all so big Dol even dare
围绕在身遵
Look at me, there at last I just have to do it
萝想就在眼前 告诉自己可以
Should 1? No Here I go
可以吗 ?不 不回顾
Just smell the grass, the dirt Just like 1 dreamed they'd be
策在草地空气散发一种香气
Just feel that summer breeze The way it's calling me
微风障阵吹起是如此的清晰
For, like, the first time ever I'm completely free
我一生中第一炊自由乱顾忌
! could go running and racing
我可以奔跑、在赛跑
And dancing and chasing
在舞跑、在跳蹈
And leaping and bounding Hair flying, heart pounding
在围绕、在嬉于 在所抱、在录胱
And splashing and reeling and finally feeling
看波涛、头要杜 我的心吗通跳
That's when my life begins
世界在我脚底
l can't believe I did this!
我真不敢相信我做到了 !
l can't believe I did this.
我真不敢相信我做到了
Mother would be so furious.
妈妈会气壤的
But that's okay. What she doesn't know won't kill her, right?
不遇没天像，她反正又不知道
Oh, my gosh! This would kill her.
天哪 ! 她一定会气球了
This is so fun!
这太好玩了 !
lam a horrible daughter. I'm going back.
我是个款女多，我要回去
lam never going back!
我绝对不回去 !
lam a despicable human being!
我是个尾部的壤人 !
Best day ever!
最棒的一天 !
You know, I can't help but notice you seem
我没闪法不注意到你似乎
a little at war with yourself here.
在跟自己天人交战
-What? -I'm only picking up bits and pieces.
-什么 ? -我只明白一小部份啦
Overprotective mother, forbidden road trip. This is serious stuff.
遇度保访的有母亲、茜止出这门 这是很严融的事
But let me ease your conscience. This is part of growing up.
不通放心好了，长大就是这样
A little rebellion, a little adventure, that's good. Healthy, even.
一点友叛、一点冒险，这很好 甚至很健康
You think?
你这广想 ?
I know. You're way over-thinking this, trust me.
是真的，虹想太多了，相信我
Does your mother deserve it? No.
母厅活该吗 ? 不
Would this break her heart and crush her soul? Of course.
这会害她伤心爱欧吗 ? 当然会
But you've got to do it.
不通炼必须要做
"Break her heart"?
“害她伤心”?
-In half. -"Crush her soul"?
-伤和了 --“害她爱警”?
Like a grape.
站出病来
She would be heartbroken. You're right.
地会心碎，你说的对
lam, aren't I? Oh, bother.
我说对了，是吗 ?真是的
All right. l can't believe I'm saying this, but I'm letting you out of the deal.
好吧，真不敢相信我会这广说 不明我让人取消交易
-What? -That's right, but don't thank me.
-什么 ? -对哎，不遇不用谢我了
Let's turn around and get you home. Here's your pan, here's your frog.
我送你回家吧，拿著锅子和青蛙
l get back my satchel,
我拿回我的包包
you get back a mother-daughter relationship based on mutual trust,
人回家做妈妈的乖女儿
and voila, we part ways as unlikely friends.
我们呢，再会啦，分道扬刍
No. lam seeing those lanterns.
不行，我要去看天煤
Oh, come on! What is it going to take for me to get my satchel back?
拜旗 ! 我要怎样才能拿回包包?
I will use this.
我会用这个
ls it ruffians? Thugs? Have they come for me?
是流让?强钦? 他们来抓我的?
Stay calm. It can probably smell fear.
冷静点，拖可能关的到你的恐己
Sorry. Guess I'm just a little bit jumpy.
对不起，我想我有吕神经遇教
Probably be best if we avoid ruffians and thugs, though.
也许我们最好这歼流谍强盗
Yeah, that would probably be best.
是啊，最好是那样
Are you hungry? I know a great place for lunch.
狐了吐? 我知道一个吃饭的好地方
Where?
哪里 ?
Don't you worry. You'll know it when you smell it.
不用担心，好到香味就知道了
A palace horse.
王室的马匹
Where's your rider?
你的硕士呢?
Rapunzel!
乐休 !
Rapunzel! Let down your hair!
乐佩 ! 放下的头权 !
I know it's around here somewhere.
我知道它就在这附近
Ah, there it is! The Snuggly Duckling.
到了 ! 风味烤鸭
Don't worry. Very quaint place. Perfect for you.
安哎，这里很有趣，很遂合你
Don't want you scaring and giving up on this whole endeavor now, do we?
你不会到到，放雍一切努力吧 ?
-Well, I do like ducklings. -Yay!
-我是还满喜数烤网的 -好耶 !
Garcon, your finest table, please!
服务生，请给我最好的位子 !
You smell that? Take a deep breath through the nose.
于到浊 ? 用鼻子深深吸一口气
Really let that seep in. What are you getting?
仔细品味一下，什么味道 ?
To me, it's part man-smell and the other part is really bad man-smell.
对我来说，有一部分是臭男人味 另一部分则是超依的男人味
I don't know why, but overall it smells like the color brown. Your thoughts?
怪的是，开起来有尿味，说啊 ?
That's a lot of hair.
好多头权哦
She's growing it out. Is that blood in your mustache?
她留的啦，你盘子上那是血吗 ?
Goldie, look at all the blood in his mustache!
金机妹，看他料子上都是血 !
Good sir, that's a lot of blood!
妈呀，血淋淋啊 !
You don't look so good, blondie. Maybe we should get you home, call it a day.
你气色不大好，人金机妹 也许你该回家，休息一天
Probably better off. This is a five-star joint.
最好是休息，这可是五星级的店
If you can't handle this place, maybe you should be back in your tower.
人受不了这和里，最好先是回塔上去
Is this you?
这是你吗 ?
-Now they're just being mean. -It's him, all right.
-他们是故意书成这样的 -是他汽错
Greno, go find some guards.
葛雷诺，快去找本其
That reward is going to buy me a new hook.
这笔赏金可以让我买副新金子了
-l could use the money. -What about me? I'm broke!
-我需要用仅 -那我呢? 我破产了 !
Get back!
退开啦 !
-Mine! -Ruffians, stop!
-我的! -流谍们，住手 !
-We can work this out! -Leave him alone!
-我们可以想想办法 ! -列伤害他 !
Gentlemen, please!
各位，拜旗 !
Give me back my guide! Ruffians!
把我的黎半还给我 ! 自流谍 !
Not the nose! Not the nose!
别打鼻子 ! 列打鼻子 !
Put him down!
把他放下 !
I don't know where I am, and I need him to take me to see the lanterns
我不知道这是哪里 我需要他带我去看天灯
because I've been dreaming about them my entire life!
因为我一草子都梦想能看到天对 !
Find your humanity! Haven't any of you ever had a dream?
你们有没有人性啊 ! 你们难道没有遇萝想吗 ?
l had a dream once.
我曾有遇一个梦想
I'm malicious, mean and scary My sneer could curdle dairy
我多狠显毒可怕 我笑更让人害怕
And violence-wise my hands are not the cleanest
恶行恶状的侯手沾满污和
But despite my evil look And my temper and my hook
长相狮锤让人抖 脾气暴躁久子手
I've always yearned to be a concert pianist
我一直芝想能锡成为钢琴手
Can't you see me on the stage performing Mozart
想像站在训上的我弹英札特
Tickling the ivories till they gleam
钢琴键被我磨得发亮
Yep, I'd rather be called deadly For my killer show tune medley
我宁顾没有分歧 册我音乐令人据息
Thank you!
谢谢 !
‘Cause way down deep inside I've got a dream
在我内心深处我有个葛
He's got a dream
他有个葛，他有个葛
See, ain't as cruel and vicious asi seem
我的内心不像外表的残暴
Though I do like breaking femurs You can count me with the dreamers
即使我党打断吧头 但是我仍有我的葛
Like everybody else I've got a dream
像其他人一样我有个欧
I've got scars and lumps and bruises Plus something here that oozes
我有伤疤采光辣青 手臂还流著有血
And let's not even mention my complexion
我的长相更是酿得不得了
But despite my extra toes And my goiter and my nose
而且多根脚下头 大甲状腺和鼻子
! really want to make a love connection
但我真的好想谈一场伙颖
Can't you see me with a special little lady?
想像在我身杂这位特别女孩
Rowing in a rowboat down the stream
带著她划船顺流而下
Though I'm one disgusting blighter I'm a lover not a fighter
即使我的长相吐心 我是情人不会打人
‘Cause way down deep inside I've got a dream
在我内心深处 我有个葛
-l've got a dream -He's got a dream
-我有个萝 -他有个葛
And I know one day romance will reign supreme
我相信恬情可以填满空洞
Though my face leaves people screaming
我的恐怖长相背和后
There's a child behind it dreaming
像个孩子一样做葛
Like everybody else, I've got a dream
和其他人一样，我有个萝
Thor would like to quit and be a florist
想爸成花下是索震的霓
Gunther does interior design
根爹他想做设计家居
-Ulf is into mime -Attila's cupcakes are sublime
-阿福演软剧 -阿提拉色香味兼具
Bruiser knits, Killer sews Fang does little puppet shows
打毛线、终衣服
And Vladimir collects ceramic unicorns
佛拉米震收藏痪资小玩意儿
-What about you? -I'm sorry, me?
-那你呢? -对不起，我?
What's your dream?
你有什么萝 ?
No, no, no. Sorry, boys. I don't sing.
不不不不，抱娄 各位，我不唱歌
! have dreams like you No, really
我就像大家都有苋
Just much less touchy-feely
很实际有用的葛
They mainly happen somewhere warm and sunny
我想在温暖晴朗地方策洞
On an island that l own Tanned and rested and alone
所有自己的岛趾 舒服享受日光浴
Surrounded by enormous piles of money
一个身尊被钱包园的美萝
-l've got a dream -She's got a dream
-我有个萝 -她有个萝
! just want to see the floating lanterns gleam
我有一个想看里浮光的萝
And with every passing hour I'm so glad I left my tower
在遇去禾个小时 我秦开塔接触现实
Like all you lovely folks I've got a dream
和朋友们一起，我有个萝
She's got a dream He's got a dream
她有个萝，他有个葛
They've got a dream We've got a dream
他们有个葛，我们有个萝
So our differences ain't really that extreme
大家差别冰不双殊
We're one big team
因为各自都腕
-Call us brutal -Sick
-手段残忍 一吐心
-Sadistic -And grotesquely optimistic
-虚待狂 -乐观得像恶魔
‘Cause way down deep inside we've got a dream
在我内心深处，我有个萝
-l've got a dream
-我有个萝
I found the guards!
我找到警卫了 !
Where's Rider? Where is he?
雷德呢? 他人在哪里?
I know he's in here somewhere. Find him.
我知道他在这里，找出他
Turn the place upside down if you have to!
必要的话把这和里拆了都行 !
Go. Live your dream.
去吧，妃求你的葛想
-I will. -Your dream stinks.
-我会的 -你的葛想烟透了
l was talking to her.
我说的是她的
Thanks for everything.
谢谢你的划忙
I believe this is the man you're looking for.
我相信这就是你要找的人
You got me!
你还到我了 !
Sir, there's no sign of Rider.
长官，找不到雷德
Maximus!
故西斯 !
What's he doing?
季在干嘛?
A passage! Come on, men. Let's go.
有密道 ! 快，跟我来
Conli! Make sure those boys don't get away.
康利 ! 列让那雨个停伙跑了
Play it safe
先求自保
or go get the crown?
有还是去追讨皇冠 ?
l got a dream ! got some dreams
我有萝想 我有好些个梦想
Somebody get me a glass!
谁快拿个杯子给我啊 !
Because I just found me a tall drink of water.
我要请大美雪喝一标
Oh, stop it, you big lug.
列关了，大人入伙
Where does that tunnel let out?
那密道通往哪里 ?
Knife!
刀子 !
I didn't know you had that in you back there. That was pretty impressive.
我不知道你那广有勇气 那真是令人印象深刻
I know!
我知道 !
I know.
我知道
So... Flynn? Where are you from?
费林，你是哪里人 ?
Whoa! Sorry, blondie, I don't do back-story.
抱娄，人金要妹，我不谈私事
However, lam becoming very interested in yours.
不明啊，我对人的事倒很感殿趣
I know I'm not supposed to mention the hair.
我知道我不该问头肾的事
-Nope. -Or the mother.
-对 -或是妈妈
-Uh-uh. -I'm too scared to ask about the frog.
-嘿咽 -我也怕问那焦青蛙
-Chameleon. -Nuance.
-变色龙 -都一样啦
Here's my question, though, if you want to see the lanterns so badly
我想问的是 如果那广想看天灯
why haven't you gone before?
那你之前干嘛不去看 ?
Well...
这个嘛…
Flynn?
费林 ?
Rider?
雷德 ?
Run. Run!
路、快跑!
-Who's that? -They don't like me.
-那是谁 ? -他们不喜数我
-They don't like me either.
-他们也不喜霓我
Who's that?
那又是谁?
Let's assume that everyone in here doesn't like me.
我们先假设过里的人都不喜欢我吧
Here.
拿去
I waited a long time for this.
这一刻我等很久了
Oh, mama! I have got to get me one of these!
妈呀 ! 我也要搞一个锅子来用用 !
You should know that this is the strangest thing I've ever done!
你该知道 这是我干遇最施县的事了 !
How about two out of three?
三战雨腾吧，如何?
Flynn, look out!
费林，小心 !
You should see your faces, because you look...
你们该去照照镜子 因为你们的科子…
.fidiculous.
笑死人
Come on, blondie! Jump!
快，金要妹!跳!
It's no use. I can't see anything.
没用的，我什么都看不到
Hey, there's no point. It's pitch-black down there.
没有用的，下面一片漆黑
She was right. I never should have done this.
她说的对，我不该这广做的
I'm so sorry, Flynn.
我很对不起，费林
Eugene.
尤金
What?
什么 ?
My real name is Eugene Fitzherbert.
我的真名叫尤金费兹柏特
Someone might as well know.
有人可能该知道
I have magic hair that glows when I sing.
我有一头我唱歌就会发光的头肾
What?
什么 ?
Il have magic hair that glows when I sing!
我有一头 我唱歌就会发光的头权 !
Flower gleam and glow Let your power shine
神被黄金花 闪耀像太阳
We made it.
我们成功了
-Her hair glows. -We're alive. I'm alive!
-她头权会发光 -我们没死，我没死 !
I didn't see that coming. The hair actually glows.
我没想到，头晏真发光了
-Why does her hair glow? -Eugene!
-她的头桶钨什么会发光 ? -尤金 !
What?
怎样啦 ?
It doesn't just glow.
它不单单只会发光
Why is he smiling at me?
拖干嘛对我笑 ?
I'll kill him. I'll kill that Rider!
我要灯了他，我要灯了雷德 !
We'll cut him off at the kingdom and get back the crown. Come on!
我们到王国那里反截他 把皇冠讨回来，我们走 !
Or...
或者…
Perhaps you want to stop acting like wild dogs
也许你们不该像雨焦野狗
chasing their tails and think for a moment.
列再追他们的尾巴筷跑 停下来想一下
Oh, please, there's no need for that.
拜旗，不用那柑啦
Well, if that's all you desire, then be on your way.
如果你们想要的就是那个 那你们可以走了
Il was going to offer you something worth 1,000 crowns.
我本想给你们价值连城的东西
Would have made you rich beyond belief,
让你们人变得有煞的不得了
and that wasn't even the best part.
那还不是最误的部份史
Oh, well. C'est fa vie. Enjoy your crown!
算了啦，享受你们的皇冠吧 !
What's the best part?
最织的部份是什么 ?
It comes with revenge on Flynn Rider.
你们还能顺便向费林雷德报优
You're being strangely cryptic
你把魔权统在我受伤的手上时
as you wrap your magic hair around my injured hand.
表情变得好神被
Sorry.
抱攻
Just don't... Don't freak out.
千菌别…嘛到了
Flower, gleam and glow
神被黄金花
Let your power shine
闪耀像太阳
Make the clock reverse
让时间倒转
Bring back what once was mine
带我回到遇往
Heal what has been hurt
疗疯蓝伤痛
Change the Fates' design
请赐我力量
Save what has been lost
重拾起失落
Bring back what once was mine
带我回到遇往
What once was mine
回到通往
Please don't freak out!
千菌别抓狂 !
I'm not freaking out. Are you freaking out?
我浊抓狂，人有抓狂吐?
I'm just interested in your hair and the magical qualities it possesses.
我只是好奇你的头权和它的魔力
How long has it been doing that exactly?
它这样多久了?
Forever, I guess.
一辈子吧，我想
Mother says when I was a baby, people tried to cut it.
妈妈说在我小时候有人想剪下它
They wanted to take it for themselves.
他们想拿回去自己用
But once it's cut, it turns brown and loses its power.
不遇它一被葛下 就会变成榨色，也失去它的魔力
A gift like that, it has to be protected.
这柑天赐的礼物，必须受到保护
That's why Mother never let me...
所以妈妈从来不让我…
That's why I never left and...
所以我从来没有郊开通…
You never left that tower.
你从来没玖并那座塔
And you're still going to go back?
而逮是要回去 ?
No! Yes.
不 ! 是的
It's complicated.
这很复杂啦
So, Eugene Fitzherbert, huh?
所以是尤金费兹柏特?
Ah, yeah. Well...
呢，对，天…
I'll spare you the sob story of poor orphan Eugene Fitzherbert.
可情孤儿尤金的悲惨故事就锡了吧
It's a little bit of a downer.
那有加悲伤
There was this book I used to read every night to all the younger kids.
那时候有一本韦 我每晚都哈给所有小朋友职
The Tales of Flynnagan Rider.
《费林根雷德传奇》
Swashbuckling rogue, richest man alive, not bad with the ladies either.
神气臭尾的大财主 女人缘也好
Not that he'd ever brag about it, of course.
这点他六没有吹牛
Was he a thief, too?
他也是一名盗贼吗?
Well, no.
不是
He had enough money to do anything that he wanted to do.
他的纱多到想干嘛都行
He could go anywhere that he wanted to go.
可以去他想去的任何地方
And for a kid with nothing, I don't know, I...
对一乱所有的孩子来说 我不知道…
Just seemed like the better option.
这似乎是比较好的人生
You can't tell anyone about this, okay?
你不能跟任何人提这件事
It could ruin my whole reputation.
这会毁了我的名融
We wouldn't want that.
我们可不想要那样
A fake reputation is all a man has.
男人最需要应假的名融
Well, I should...
我应该…
I should get some more firewood.
我应该去多再点柴火
For the record, I like Eugene Fitzherbert much better than Flynn Rider.
说实话，我喜欢尤金费兹柏特
Then you'd be the first. But thank you.
那你还是第一个了，不过谢计
Well, I thought he'd never leave.
我以贺他不走了啊
Mother?
妈妈 ?
Hello, dear.
你好，守上中
How did you find me?
称怎广找到我的?
It was easy, really.
其实挺简章的
I just listened for the sound of complete and utter betrayal and followed that.
我聆芭背叛的静音 跟著它
-We're going home. Now. -You don't understand.
-我们现在就回家 -炼不明白
I've been on this incredible journey, and I've seen and learned so much.
我的旅程钴彩扰比 我看到也学到了很多
l even met someone.
我晃认识了一个人
Yes, the wanted thief. I'm so proud. Come on.
对，通缉要犯，我好磺合，走吧
Mother, wait. I think...
妈妈 ，等等，我想…
Likes you? Please, Rapunzel, that's demented!
喜欢你?拜斌，那太瞎了吧 !
This is why you never should have left
这是你不该苑家的原因
Dear, this whole romance that you've invented
厅爱的 人以贺自己遇见了罗曼史
Just proves you're too naive to be here
证明你太天真不该出门
Why would he like you? Come on now, really
他篇什么要喜数上媒
Look at you! You think that he's impressed?
看看你 ! 以为他欣赏你 ?
Don't be a dummy, come with Mummy
列当傻瓜，跟我回家
Mother...
妈妈…
No!
不 !
No?
不?
Oh, I see how it is
吗，我可明白了
Rapunzel knows best Rapunzel's so mature now
乐傈你匠好，人已经长大
Such a clever grown-up miss
是个隐明成熟的女孩
Rapunzel knows best Fine, if you're so sure now
人心里了解，再肯定也不过
-Go ahead, then give him this! -How did you...
-去把过个交给他 ! -称怎广…
This is why he's here Don't let him deceive you
它就是原因 交给他列猫移
Give it to him, watch, you'll see
不要让他苏骗人
I will!
我会的 !
Trust me, my dear That's how fast he'll leave you
职我的话，他会马上效开
! won't say I told you so
我会忘掉这件事
No, Rapunzel knows best So, if he's such a dreamboat
你心里最了解 若他是如此迷人
Go and put him to the test
让他接受这考验
Mother, wait!
妈妈 ，等等
If he's lying, don't come crying
没有决心，没有信心
Mother knows best
我最了解
So, can l ask you something?
我可以问虹一件事吗 ?
Is there any chance that I'm going to get super strength in my hand?
我有没有机会让我的手 反有超级神力 ?
Because I'm not going to lie. That would be stupendous.
因为说实话，那柑会很了不起耶
Hey, you all right?
炼还好吧 ?
Sorry, yes. Just lost in thought, I guess.
抱娄，我还好 我刚刚在想事情
Here's the thing,
是这样的
superhuman good looks, I've always had them. Born with it.
超级印哥 我一向很印，天生的
But superhuman strength. Can you imagine the possibilities of this?
不遇超神力证哥 你能想像这个可能性吗 ?
Patience, boys.
十位，别心委
All good things to those who wait.
好事多魔
Well, hope you're here to apologize.
我希望你是来道娄的
No, put me down. Stop it! No!
放我下来，停 ! 不要 !
Let me go!
放并我 !
Give me him!
把他给我 !
Easy, boy. Easy! Settle down.
冷静点 ! 冷静下来
That's it.
就是这样
Now sit.
快坐下
Sit!
坐下 !
-What? -Now drop the boot.
-什么 ? -放下翰子
Drop it.
放下
You're such a good boy! Yes, you are!
你真是个乖孩子 ! 你好乎 !
You all tired from chasing this bad man all over the place?
你追这个壤像伙追的好累哦
-Excuse me? -Nobody appreciates you, do they?
-这什么啊? -都没有人感激你，对吧 ?
Do they?
对吧?
Oh, come on. He's a bad horse!
拜旗，物是一匹壤马 !
Oh, he's nothing but a big sweetheart.
拖是超级大甜心
Isn't that right...
对不对…
Maximus?
过西到斯?
You've got to be kidding me.
这也太扯了吧
Look. Today is kind of the biggest day of my life,
区著，今天是我最重要的一天
and the thing is, I need you not to get him arrested.
我想说的是 我要你列让他被人抓走
Just for 24 hours,
只要24小时
and then you can chase each other to your heart's content.
之后你爱怎广追就怎麻追
And it's also my birthday. Just so you know.
顺便告诉你，今天也是我生日
Excuse me. Sorry.
抱娄，借明
Thank you!
谢谢 !
It's for the lost princess.
这是给失中公主的
To the boats!
到船焉去 !
Hey, Max!
堆斯 !
What? I bought them.
怎样 ? 我买的啦
Most of them.
大部分都是
Where are we going?
我们要去哪 ?
Best day of your life? I figured you should have a decent seat.
你这介子最议的一天 我想你应该要有个好位子
You okay?
炼还好吧 ?
I'm terrified.
我听款了
Why?
为什么 ?
I've been looking out a window for 18 years,
我从窗口向外望18年了
dreaming about what it might feel like when those lights rise in the sky.
想像望著那些灯火升上天订时 会有什么感觉
What if it's not everything that dreamed it would be?
蓝一跟我想像的不一样呢 ?
It will be.
会一样的
And what if it is? What do I do then?
菌一一样呢? 那我该怎广办 ?
That's the good part, I guess. You get to go find a new dream.
我想那是件好事 你就可以去找新的葛想
All those days watching from the windows
每一天独自站在窗遵
All those years, outside looking in
每一年晃望闭速处
All that time, never even knowing
每一刻从来都不知道
Just how blind I've been
我有多育目
Now I'm here, blinking in the starlight
看看我，集立在星光下
Now I'm here, suddenly I see
好让我画收在眼底
Standing here, it's, oh, so clear
这一切如此清晰
I'm where I'm meant to be
我认清我自己
And at last 1 see the light
终藉我可以明白
And it's like the fog has lifted
就像是迷需里散去
And it's like the sky is new
像眼前闪亮星空
And it's warm and real and bright
如此温暖而真实
And the world has somehow shifted
一切似乎已经改变
All at once, everything looks different
章那间，一切变得不同
Now that I see you
因为我有你
l have something for you, too.
我也有东西要送你
I should have given it to you before, but I was just scared.
我早就该给你了，可是我很害怕
And the thing is, I'm not scared anymore. You know what I mean?
不遇现在，我再也不怕了 你懂我的意思吗 ?
I'm starting to.
我并始明白了
All those days chasing down a daydream
每一天追逐著和白日萝
All those years, living in a blur
那一年荒唐明日子
All that time, never truly seeing
每一刻我从来不曾
Things the way they were
有过看清一切
Now she's here, shining in the starlight
看看她，在夜空下内炮
Now she's here, suddenly I know
只有她，在我的眼底
If she's here, it's crystal clear
因为她，我的存在
I'm where I'm meant to go
有了新的意义
And at last 1 see the light
终藉我可以明白
And it's like the fog has lifted
就像是迷需里散去
And it's like the sky is new
像眼前闪亮星空
And it's warm and real and bright
如此温暖而真实
And the world has somehow shifted
一切似乎已经改变
All at once, everything is different
章那间，一切变得不同
Now that I see you
因为我有你
see you
有你
Is everything okay?
你没事吧 ?
Oh, yes.
没事
Yes, of course. I just...
当然没事，我只是…
I'm sorry. Everything is fine.
对不起，一切都很好
There's just something I have to take care of.
只不遇我有件事要去处理一下
Okay.
好吧
I'll be right back.
我马上回来
It's all right, Pascal.
没关像啦，帕斯卡
There you are!
你们在这里啊 !
I've been searching everywhere for you guys since we got separated.
我们走散后，我一直在找你们
The sideburns are coming in nice, huh? Got to be excited about that.
费角挺捉的六 一定很拉风
Anyhow, I just wanted to say I shouldn't have split.
恕之，我只想说我不该落跑
The crown is all yours. I'll miss you, but I think it's for the best.
皇冠是你们的了，我会想念你们 不明我想这样…最好
Holding out on us again, eh, Rider?
又想路弄我们啊，雷德 ?
-What? -We heard you found something.
-什么 ? -职说你找到好东西
Something much more valuable than a crown.
比皇冠更值袋的好东西
We want her instead.
我们要她
I was starting to think you ran off with the crown and left me.
我以为你拿了皇冠就去下我了
He did.
他是没错
What? No. He wouldn't.
什么 ? 不，他才不会
See for yourself.
自己看吧
Eugene?
尤金?
Eugene!
尤金 !
A fair trade. A crown for the girl with the magic hair.
这交易划算 用皇冠换一个魔归少女
How much do you think someone would pay to stay young and healthy forever?
你想人们禹了永保青春和健康 会顾意花多少钱?
No. Please. No!
不，拜旗，不要 !
Rapunzel!
乐休 !
Mother?
妈妈 ?
Oh, my precious girl!
我的裤具女儿1!
Mother.
妈妈
Are you all right? Are you hurt?
逮好吧 ? 你没受伤吧 ?
-How did you... -l was so worried about you, dear.
-你怎么会… -我好担心你，裤具
So I followed you. And I saw them attack you and...
所以我跟跳你 接著我看到他们攻击…
Oh, my. Let's go before they come to!
天哪，趁他们醒来之前快走 !
You were right, Mother. You were right about everything.
你说的对，妈杂 你每一件事都说对了
I know, darling. I know.
我知道，裤贝，我知道
Look!
快看 !
The crown!
皇冠 !
No! Wait, guys!
不!等等!
Let's get this over with, Rider.
让我们了结这一切吧
Where are we going?
我们要去哪 ?
There. It never happened.
好了，忘了这一切吧
Now, wash up for dinner. I'm making hazelnut soup.
快去梳洗，准人备吃癸 我煮标子淡温哦
l really did try, Rapunzel. I tried to warn you what was out there.
我真的试遇了，乐佩 我试著丈告你外面的世界
The world is dark and selfish and cruel.
那世界黑暗自私又残酷
If it finds even the slightest ray of sunshine,
就算天堂有一滴阳光滴下来
it destroys it.
也会被它摧毁
How did you know about her? Tell me, now!
你们怎庆会知道她的事? 快说 !
It wasn't us! It was the old lady!
不是我们 ! 是那个老太朔 !
Old lady?
老太婆?
Wait. No! Wait!
等一下，不! 等等!
You don't understand! She's in trouble! Wait!
你们不明白，她有麻烦 ! 等等 !
What's going on up there?
发生什么事了?
Are you all right?
炼还好吧 ?
I'm the lost princess.
我是失号的公主
Please speak up, Rapunzel. You know how I hate the mumbling.
说话大声点，知道我讨屡碎碎哈
lam the lost princess. Aren't I?
我就是失跳的公主，对吧?
Did 1 mumble, Mother?
我还碎碎啥吗，妈奸?
Or should I even call you that?
或者我不该叫虹杂?
Rapunzel, do you even hear yourself?
乐休，你贩匠人自己说的话
Why would you ask such a ridiculous question?
你怎广会癌这广克谱的问题 ?
It was you! It was all you!
是你 ! 就是干的!
Everything I did was to protect you.
我做的一切都是为了保护你
I've spent my entire life hiding from people who would use me for my power
我花了一莫子时间 躲避那些想利用我魔力的人
when I should have been hiding from you!
而我最该躲的人全是 !
Where will you go? He won't be there for you.
你要去哪? 他不会等你的
What did you do to him?
你对他做了什么 ?
That criminal is to be hanged for his crimes.
那个罪犯就要被押去处死了
-No. -Now, now, it's all right.
一不 -好了，没事了
Listen to me. All of this is as it should be.
职我说，一切都该如此
No! You were wrong about the world.
不 ! 你错看了这个世界
And you were wrong about me!
刀错看了我 !
And I will never let you use my hair again!
我不会再让姬用我的头要了 !
You want me to be the bad guy?
你要我当款人?
Fine, now I'm the bad guy.
好，那我就当款人
What's this?
搞什么 ?
Open up!
雪门上!
-What's the password? -What?
-通明密语是什么 ? -什么 ?
-Nope. -Open this door!
-不对 -给我开门 !
Not even close!
也差太速了 !
You have three seconds! One...
给你三秒娓 ! 一…
Two...
人
Three.
一
Frying pans! Who knew, right?
平底人饥 ! 想不到吧 ?
-Head down.
-低头
-Arms in.
-手夹紧
-Knees apart. -Knees apart. Knees apart?
-肤盖分并 -肤盖分并，肤盖分并 ?
Why do I need to keep my knees apart...
我干嘛要分并膝萃…
Max! You brought them here?
故斯 ! 你带他们来的?
Thank you.
谢谢
No, really. Thank you.
真的，谢谢你
we've just been misunderstanding one another,
我们一直都误解了彼此
and we're really just...
我们真的该…
You're right, we should go.
你说的对，我们是该走了
Max?
故斯 ?
Okay, Max. Let's see how fast you can run.
好吧，让我看看你能跑多快
Rapunzel?
乐仇 ?
Rapunzel, let down your hair!
乐何，放下你的头肾 !
Rapunzel, thought I'd never see you again.
乐侣，我以锅我再也见不到人了
Now look what you've done, Rapunzel.
看看虹造成的恶果
Oh, don't worry, dear. Our secret will die with him.
不用担心，裤具 我们的秘密会跟著他死去
And as for us...
至於我们…
We are going where no one will ever find you again.
我们要去一个 不再有人能找到虹的地方
Rapunzel, really!
乐休，金了 !
Enough already! Stop fighting me!
角了 !列再反抗了!
No! I won't stop!
不了 ! 我不会停止了 !
For every minute of the rest of my life, I will fight!
这草子的每一刻，我都会反抗了 !
I will never stop trying to get away from you!
我永直都会设法逃苑人了 !
But if you let me save him, I will go with you.
不明要是你让我救他 我就会跟你走
No! No, Rapunzel.
不 1不要，乐佩
I'll never run. I'll never try to escape.
我不会逃跑 我永趟不会党试逃走
Just let me heal him and you and I will be together,
只要让我救他 你和我就可以一起
forever, just like you want.
一募子，如炼所顾
Everything will be the way it was.
一切都会像以前一样
Just like you want.
如虹所顾
Just let me heal him.
只要让我救他
In case you get any ideas about following us.
以防你事后想追我们
I'm so sorry. Everything is going to be okay, though.
对不起，一切都不会有事的
No, Rapunzel.
不，乐佩
I promise. You have to trust me. Come on. Just breathe.
我保证，你要相信我，快呼吸
I can't let you do this.
我不能让巡广做
And I can't let you die.
我也不能让你死
But if you do then you will die.
要是你这广做，就会死
Hey. It's going to be all right.
不会有事的
Wait.
等等
Eugene...
尤金…
No!
不 !
What have you done?
你做了什么好事 ?
No, no, no. Eugene.
不，尤金
No! Look at me. I'm right here. Don't go. Stay with me.
不 !看著我，我就在这祷 列死，你别死
Flower, gleam and glow Let your power shine
神被黄金花 闪耀像太阳
Make the clock reverse Bring back what once was mine
让时间倒转 带我回到遇往
What?
什么 ?
And you were mine.
你也是我的
Heal what has been hurt
疗疯蓝伤痛
Change the Fates' design
请赐我力量
Save what has been lost
重拾起失落
Bring back what once was mine
带我回到遇往
What once was mine
回到通往
Rapunzel?
乐仇 ?
Eugene?
尤金?
Did I ever tell you I've got a thing for brunettes?
我跟你提遇我很哈棕权妹吐?
Well, you can imagine what happened next.
你们可以想像接下来的发展
The kingdom rejoiced, for their lost princess had returned,
全国上下霓欣大贺 他们失号的公主回来了
The party lasted an entire week, and honestly 1 don't remember most of it.
静乐派对持续一整过 说真的，我大多都记不得了
That guy went on to become the most famous concert pianist in the world,
那信伙成了最知名的钢琴家
if you can believe it!
你敢相信吗 ?
And this guy? He eventually found true love.
而这信人炙?他膛真的找到了真爱
As for this guy, l assume he's happy. He's never told me otherwise.
他没开口跟我说遇啦
Thanks to Maximus,
感潮礁西玛斯
crime in the kingdom disappeared almost overnight.
整个王国的罪犯一夜之间都消失了
As did most of the apples.
整个王国的葛果也是
Pascal never changed.
帕斯卡完全没伙
At last Rapunzel was home. And she finally had a real family.
至少，乐休回家了 她也终藉有了真正的家人
She was a princess worth waiting for.
她是一位值得等待的公主
Beloved by all, she led her kingdom with all the grace and wisdom
她受囚人爱戴，以智慧领导王国
that her parents did before her.
就像她父母一样
And, as for me, ! started going by Eugene again,
至於我，我以尤金之名重出江湖
stopped thieving and turned it all around.
不再偷盗，所行好事
But I know what the big question is.
不明我知道你们最想问的是什说
Did Rapunzel and I ever get married?
乐修和我到底有没有结婚?
I'm pleased to tell you
我很荣幸告诉你们
that after years and years of asking and asking and asking...
经遇年复一年不断的请求…
I finally said yes.
我终从答应了
-Eugene. -All right, l asked her.
-尤金 -好噶，是我向她求婚的
And we're living happily ever after.
我们从此遇闭幸福快乐的生活
Yes, we are.
是啊，没错
English - US
Mandarin Traditional